A Guide to the Mullens Smokeless Coal Company Records 1937-60, n.d.
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Mullens Smokeless Coal Company Records 1937-60, n.d.
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms94-005
2.0 cu. ft., 4 folders, 17 ledgers
Purchased at auction on March 23, 1994.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
Based in Mullens, West Virginia, The Mullens Smokeless Coal Company was owned and operated by Harry Meade. The company was also known as Harmco Smokeless Coal Company in the 1950s.
Scope and Content Information
The Mullens Smokeless Coal Company records consist mainly of ledgers and cash books which detail company accounts, coal buyers, and billings. Also included are certificates of capital stock, Mining Laws from the West Virginia Legislature, and various publications pertaining to coal mining.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged according to subject matter.
Index Terms
Coal Mining; Mullens Smokeless Coal Company; West Virginia
Contents List
- Mullens Smokeless Coal Company Records 1937-60
  - Stock Certificates, Publications, Proposed Revisions, Ledgers
    - Stock Certificates 1940, 1952 (Box-folder 1-1)
      Three stock certificates and two hypothecation agreements between the company and the Raleigh County Bank.
    - Harmco Smokeless Coal Company: Publications 1953, 1955, n.d. (Box-folder 1-2)
      Four items: Hitchcock's Resale Guide (1953), Barber-Greene Conveyors Catalog (1953), Mechanization: The Magazine of Modern Coal (March, 1955), and Westinghouse: The Use of Modern Drives for Modern Coal Mining (n.d.)
    - Mining Laws, Parts I-IV, Legislative Interim Committee, West Virginia Legislature November, 1942 (Box-folder 1-3)
    - Blank Stationary Pages n.d. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Ledgers
    - Cash Book 1937-43 (Box 1)
      75 pages
    - Ledgers 1937-40 (Box 1)
      Coal Shipments, December 1937 to September 1938; Ledger of the Nuriva Smokeless Coal Company - coal shipments, November 1938 to January 1939; Ledger of the Mullens Smokeless Coal Company - coal shipments, February 1939 to January 1940
    - Invoice Registers 1937-1942 (Box 1)
      Arbutus Coal Company - Invoice Register, December 1937 to September 1938; Nuriva Smokeless Coal Company, November 1938 to December 1938; Mullens Smokeless Coal Company - Invoices, January 1939 to August 1942
    - Account Ledger 1930-44 (Box 1)
    - Account Ledger 1940-41 (Box 2)
    - Inventory Ledger 1941-42 (Box 2)
    - Account Book 1942-46 (Box 2)
    - Inventory Ledger 1942-44 (Box 2)
      Details customer orders and shipments.
    - Ledger of Store Invoices 1943-49 (Box 2)
    - Cash Book of Supplies Paid for 1943-49 (Box 2)
    - Ledger of Coal Buyers 1944-46 (Box 2)
    - Ledger of Coal Buyers 1946-50 (Box 2)
    - Ledger of Billing 1946-50 (Box 2)
    - Accounting Book of Payment and Payroll 1947-53 (Box 2)
    - Accounting Book of Tad Smokeless Coal Company Billing 1949-50 (Box 2)
    - Ledger of Murphy Buildly 1949-53 (Box 2)
      Murphy Buildly Ledger, November 1949 to April 1950; Harmco Smokeless Coal Company Buyers, October 1952 to March 1953; Mullens Smokeless Coal Company Buyers, July 1953 to September 1953
    - Cash Book of Personal Accounts of Evelyn Meade 1956-60 (Box 2)